Arbaaz Sumar

Front End Developer

Meticulous front end developer with over 2 years of experience with a passion for React and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. I am eager to continue my career by joining a hardworking and interactive team where I will continue expanding my front-end knowledge into perfecting performance and efficiency.

arbaaz970@gmail.com

+254705913300

Nairobi, Kenya Relocation / Remote Possible

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

Experience

11/2020 to present

Front End Developer

Freelance, Remote

- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Created a user experience that fetched, parsed, and formatted analytic data, and relayed it into React components.
- Built mock designs and wireframes for landing pages for 5 new product concepts.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5, and CSS3, which improved user satisfaction by 40%.
- Designed and developed web applications using React.js to increase target audience engagement by 15%.

05/2020 to 10/2020

Junior Front End Developer Real Biz Digital LTD, Nairobi

- Created a Mobile Responsive User Experience with CSS Flexbox that allowed cross-platform accessibility to the website on any device with primary use on mobile. This increased the number of 5-star User Experience/User Interface reviews by 360%
- Assisted the development team in maintaining 8 websites.
- Implemented front-end technical solutions to meet project requirements for creation of 5 new web pages.
- Ensured 6 unique projects complied with correct technology processes, industry best practices, and company standards.
- Conducted research and assisted with new business scoping efforts, resulting in the acquisition of 4 clients.
- Worked in an Agile, collaborative environment to receive design requirements, peer program, and test applications.

Skills

Languages

JavaScript, Python, NodeJS, SQL

Frontend

React, NextJs, Vue

Other

Redux, Tailwind, AWS, Git

Education

Bachelor of Science: Applied Computer & Technology 2016–2020 Nairobi, Kenya

United States International University Africa

Certifications

Frontend Developer Career Path

Scrimba